Yannis ...
Yannis ...
Where's the literary?
Di mana sastra?
I am here because he is not there, Osman.
Saya di sini karena dia tidak ada di sana, Osman.
Defraud the word! Answer my question.
Menipu kata! Jawab pertanyaanku.
Edebali and her daughter are gone.
Edebali dan putrinya pergi.
But I don't know where they are.
Tapi saya tidak tahu di mana mereka.
It will not take long.
Tidak akan lama.
Remember that it is at the tip of my claw.
Ingat itu di ujung cakar saya.
Killing me ...
Membunuhku ...
Osman is the last thing you want right now.
Osman adalah hal terakhir yang Anda inginkan saat ini.
Demon.
Iblis.
Selcan Hatun.
Selcan Hatun.
What are you saying?
Apa yang kamu katakan
Selcan Hatun is not even in the willow.
Selcan Hatun bahkan tidak ada di pohon willow.
Your anger overshadowed your intelligence, Osman.
Kemarahan Anda membayangi kecerdasan Anda, Osman.
You forget that we have a dark shadow in every nook.
Anda lupa bahwa kami memiliki bayangan gelap di setiap sudut.
What did you do to Selcan Hatun?
Apa yang Anda lakukan pada Selcan Hatun?
You, not us, will decide.
Anda, bukan kami, yang akan memutuskan.
Now in the caravanserai, unaware of everything ...
Sekarang di karavan, tidak menyadari segalanya ...
... he is staying.
... ia tinggal.
Welcome, Princess Sofia.
Selamat datang, Putri Sofia.
We're [I'm] glad to be here.
Hoşbulduk.
What are you looking for, Selcan Hatun?
Apa yang kamu cari, Selcan Hatun?
My dagger is here, but Hayme Ana's ...
Belati saya ada di sini, tapi Hayme Ana ...
... I can't find an heirloom dagger.
... Saya tidak dapat menemukan belati pusaka.
You go ahead and eat.
Anda pergi ke depan dan makan.
Here my princess
Di sini putri saya
To that table ...
Ke meja itu ...
... send fruit with plenty of goat meat
... kirim buah dengan banyak daging kambing
What's up?
Tidak ada itu?
What are these?
Apa ini
Kulucahisar princess is the treat of Sofia ...
Putri Kulucahisar adalah suguhan Sofia ...
... Selcan hatun
... Selcan hatun
If I don't survive here ...
Jika saya tidak bertahan di sini ...
... I'm a man outside ...
... Saya seorang pria di luar ...
... he's waiting to fly news to the caravanserai.
... dia menunggu untuk menerbangkan berita ke karavan.
Are you ready to negotiate with your devil, Osman?
Apakah Anda siap untuk bernegosiasi dengan iblis Anda, Osman?
What do you want?
Apa yang kamu inginkan
For my dear ...
Untuk sayangku ...
... Selcan's soul.
... Jiwa Selcan.
you are lying
Anda berbohong
To get rid of my hand ...
Untuk menyingkirkan tanganku ...
a lie you made up.
sebuah kebohongan yang kau buat.
I am grateful that you accepted my offer.
Saya bersyukur Anda menerima tawaran saya.
It's not a holiday, it's not watching ...
Ini bukan hari libur, tidak menonton ...
... why are you served?
... mengapa kamu dilayani?
You are a guest.
Anda seorang tamu.
The catering to the guest is from the glory of the host.
Katering untuk tamu adalah dari kemuliaan tuan rumah.
Can I sit?
Bisakah saya duduk
The fool of the guest thought he was the host.
Si bodoh tamu mengira dia adalah tuan rumah.
This dormitory is ours.
Asrama ini milik kita.
As for the guest,
Adapun tamu,
If you agree to be a guest at my desk ...
Jika Anda setuju untuk menjadi tamu di meja saya ...
... come on, sit down.
... ayolah, duduk.
As you wish.
Apapun yang kamu mau.
So, you are the famous Selcan Hatun.
Jadi, Anda adalah Selcan Hatun yang terkenal.
He saw the day in Kulucahisar
Dia melihat hari di Kulucahisar
Even Greek women praise your name.
Bahkan wanita Yunani memuji nama Anda.
We look at the stove, not the fire.
Kami melihat kompor, bukan api.
Although Nam is ours, the trick is Hayme Mother.
Meskipun Nam adalah milik kita, triknya adalah Ibu Hayme.
I am sure...
Saya yakin ...
... grandson of Hayme Ana ...
... cucu dari Hayme Ana ...
...Mr. Osman.
Osman Bey.
He will be very happy to see you.
Dia akan sangat senang melihatmu.
Kinship is also howling princess.
Kekerabatan juga melolong putri.
However, Osman is my child.
Namun, Osman adalah anak saya.
Elbet, I miss him too.
Elbet, aku juga merindukannya.
Well, let's see
Baiklah, mari kita lihat
Why is this relation to Osman?
Mengapa hubungan ini dengan Osman?
Osman Bey found the murderers of my husband and sentenced him.
Osman Bey menemukan pembunuh suamiku dan menghukumnya.
In our eyes, its value is great.
Di mata kami, nilainya sangat bagus.
Did you recognize this dagger, Osman?
Apakah Anda mengenali belati ini, Osman?
Hayme Ana
Hayme Ana
If you say no to my offer, Selcan Hatun ...
Jika Anda menolak tawaran saya, Selcan Hatun ...
... will need this dagger a lot.
... akan membutuhkan belati ini banyak.
My main is half. If you do any harm to her ...
Utama saya setengah. Jika Anda melakukan salahnya ...
... if you are in the well where there are snakes, I will take you off with my hands.
... jika Anda berada di sumur di mana ada ular, saya akan membawa Anda pergi dengan tangan saya.
Osman is not over yet.
Osman belum berakhir.
Not only my dear, but Aybars ...
Bukan hanya sayangku, tapi Aybars ...
... I will give the murderers.
... Aku akan memberikan para pembunuh.
Subject...
Tentu ...
You will not sound my execution.
Anda tidak akan membunyikan eksekusi saya.
Selcan Hatun?
Selcan Hatun?
It will reach the plain unharmed. Now think well.
Ini akan mencapai dataran tanpa terluka. Sekarang pikirkan baik-baik.
Either leaving here and going to the castle ...
Entah meninggalkan sini dan pergi ke kastil ...
... testify to my execution
... bersaksi untuk eksekusi saya
or ..
atau ..
Taking revenge on Aybars' murderers ...
Membalas para pembunuh Aybars ...
... turning to oba
... beralih ke oba
You will get Selcan Hatun, which you love as much as your mother.
Anda akan mendapatkan Selcan Hatun, yang sangat Anda cintai seperti ibu Anda.
This was a big game, wasn't it?
Ini pertandingan besar, bukan?
I am the only one who knows you.
Saya satu-satunya yang mengenal Anda.
You will be lost and disappear.
Anda akan terhilang dan hilang.
Here is Osman Bey I know
Ini Osman Bey yang saya tahu
it.
ini.
Both brave and intelligent.
Berani dan cerdas.
Don't forget that I am brutal!
Jangan lupa bahwa saya brutal!
I...
Saya ...
I'm a dead man, Osman.
Saya sudah mati, Osman.
Where are Aybars murderers?
Di mana pembunuh Aybars?
They're in the black forest right now.
Mereka ada di hutan hitam sekarang.
At the beginning ...
Pada awalnya ...
... there is Salvador.
... ada Salvador.
Mr. Osman!
Osman Bey!
Hurry up.
Cepatlah.
Who will hurt this time ...
Siapa yang akan terluka kali ini ...
I can't even take a nap.
Aku bahkan tidak bisa tidur siang.
This isn't over, Yannis.
Ini belum berakhir, Yannis.
In those dark shadows
Dalam bayangan gelap itu
that bat on your face
kelelawar di wajahmu
I will drown with the light of my pus, you know.
Saya akan tenggelam dengan cahaya nanah saya, Anda tahu.
Our holy cause is for our master Yannis.
Tujuan suci kita adalah untuk tuan kita Yannis.
For our holy cause and master Yannis.
Untuk tujuan suci kita dan tuan Yannis.
Thanks to Osman Bey
Terima kasih untuk Osman Bey
into this land
ke tanah ini
we cut out a big ur.
kami memotong ur besar.
Osman, as much as a hunter ...
Osman, sebanyak pemburu ...
... proved to be a great Bey.
... terbukti menjadi Bey yang hebat.
Why did Osman not come?
Kenapa Osman tidak datang?
You need to know that, Mr. Bamsi.
Anda perlu tahu itu, Tuan Bamsi.
Not in Sofia.
Bukan di Sofia.
Mr. Gündüz,
Tuan Gündüz,
There's a hell going around here.
Ada banyak hal yang terjadi di sini.
When my Osman comes, I will learn all of them.
Ketika Osman saya datang, saya akan mempelajari semuanya.
So, where's Osman Osman Dundar?
Jadi, di mana Osman Osman Dundar?
Is there any reason that makes Osman's works a secret?
Adakah alasan yang membuat rahasia karya Osman?
You'll see, it ends soon.
Anda akan melihat, itu segera berakhir.
Ea ...
Ea ...
now this carcass ...
sekarang bangkai ini ...
... What do you know is Yannis melunu?
... Apa yang kamu tahu adalah Yannis melunu?
What if?
Bagaimana jika?
Osman is the only one who knows him other than us.
Osman adalah satu-satunya yang mengenalnya selain kita.
He did not come to death.
Dia tidak mati.
Trust us, Mr. Bamsi.
Percayalah pada kami, Tn. Bamsi.
Even the carcass of someone like Yannis
Bahkan bangkai seseorang seperti Yannis
It pollutes Kulucahisar's air.
Itu mencemari udara Kulucahisar.
Take it.
Ambillah.
Mr. Alişar
Tuan Alişar
while you are here
selagi kamu di sini
Old agreement in your hospitality
Perjanjian lama dalam keramahan Anda
we wish to renew.
kami ingin memperbarui.
Here you are, Hazrat Alişar.
Ini dia, Hazrat Alişar.
Mr. Dundar.
Pak Dundar.
Day
hari
I'm not comfortable at all.
Saya tidak nyaman sama sekali.
Your uncle is still pursuing an agreement.
Pamanmu masih mengejar kesepakatan.
My Osman is still not around.
Osman saya masih belum ada.
Don't worry, Mr. Bamsi
Jangan khawatir, Tuan Bamsi
the basics of this agreement
dasar-dasar perjanjian ini
my father Ertuğrul Gazi threw.
ayah saya Ertuğrul Gazi melemparkan.
Ertuğrul Bey, this agreement
Ertuğrul Bey, perjanjian ini
He hoped to do it with Yorgo Pulos.
Dia berharap bisa melakukannya dengan Yorgo Pulos.
This is not with couds.
Ini bukan dengan couds.
Mr. Gündüz ...
Tuan Gündüz ...
not with these couds.
tidak dengan couds ini.
not with it
tidak dengan itu
where are you my dear
dimana kamu sayangku
Where?
Dimana?
Duh!
Duh!
No, no?
Tidak, tidak?
As if he had received good news
Seolah dia telah menerima kabar baik
You have a condition.
Anda memiliki suatu kondisi.
Thank god it will cost you a lot
Terima kasih Tuhan akan dikenakan biaya banyak
They dealt with an unpleasant issue.
Mereka berurusan dengan masalah yang tidak menyenangkan.
Your foot came auspicious.
Kakimu datang menguntungkan.
For your guest curtain
Untuk tirai tamu Anda
thank you.
terima kasih
I'm glad to meet you.
Senang bertemu denganmu.
If you let me
Jika kamu membiarkan aku
you and Zöhre Hatun
Anda dan Zöhre Hatun
I would like to visit in Obanız.
Saya ingin mengunjungi di Obanız.
Of course.
Tentu saja.
Our door is always open to friends.
Pintu kami selalu terbuka untuk teman-teman.
(Salutes)
(Salut)
Aybüke, who are they?
Aybüke, siapa mereka?
I couldn't take it out, Selcan Hatun.
Saya tidak bisa mengambilnya, Selcan Hatun.
Beautiful girl, who are you from?
Gadis cantik, dari siapa kamu?
Where does it come from, where do you go?
Dari mana datangnya, kemana kamu pergi?
Ahi Evran with his comrade ahiler ...
Ahi Evran dengan ahiler rekannya ...
We remember Fatma aunty Yaren.
Kami ingat Fatma bibi Yaren.
Who is this four man with you?
Siapakah keempat pria ini bersamamu?
My father.
Ayah saya.
Is Sheikh Edebali.
Apakah Sheikh Edebali.
Can I disturb if I come to your side?
Bisakah saya mengganggu jika saya datang ke sisi Anda?
My father also loves to pray and mother.
Ayah saya juga suka berdoa dan ibu.
On the contrary, he would be pleased.
Sebaliknya, dia akan senang.
Hay, thank you.
Hay, terima kasih.
You shine like dir, my beautiful girl.
Kamu bersinar seperti dir, gadis cantikku.
Let me illuminate my path.
Biarkan saya menerangi jalan saya.
Estağfirullah, chick.
Estağfirullah, cewek.
If we had allowed you, we would have shown our respect, sir.
Jika kami mengizinkan Anda, kami akan menunjukkan rasa hormat kami, tuan.
Adap, claw in front of a mortal ...
Adap, cakar di depan manusia ...
... the sofa is not stopping, chick.
... sofa tidak berhenti, cewek.
Edep in the face of the glory of the Creator ...
Edep di muka kemuliaan Sang Pencipta ...
... knowing your absence, nothingness.
... mengetahui ketidakhadiranmu, ketiadaan.
Hay, thank you.
Hay, terima kasih.
They did not call you Turkmen Husband in vain.
Mereka tidak memanggilmu Suami Turkmen dengan sia-sia.
You entered the big caravanserai with your light, shaken it with your majesty ...
Anda memasuki karavan besar dengan cahaya Anda, mengocoknya dengan keagungan Anda ...
... you burned with wisdom.
... Anda dibakar dengan kebijaksanaan.
Excuse me.
Permisi
Can you donate your name, babe?
Bisakah kamu menyumbangkan namamu, sayang?
The mother of martyr, martyred court, Selcan Hatun from apricot.
Ibu dari martir, pengadilan yang syahid, Selcan Hatun dari aprikot.
[They're swelling the sword. ]
[Mereka membengkak pedang. ]
[Laughter sounds.]
[Suara tawa.]
Be careful just in case brothers.
Hati-hati kalau-kalau saudara.
Storm!
Bora!
Hello, sir.
Halo, tuan.
You hold the Kangaroo and Boğaç right side.
Anda memegang sisi kanan Kanguru dan Boga.
Don't let anyone escape.
Jangan biarkan siapa pun melarikan diri.
Thank you, Mr.
Terima kasih tuan
Lets!
Ayo!
Hold the back side with Onur, Demir bent and Erkut.
Pegang sisi belakang dengan Onur, Demir membungkuk dan Erkut.
We will attack with my sign.
Kami akan menyerang dengan tanda saya.
There is no scabbard to enter pusat in our waist from now on.
Tidak ada sarung untuk memasuki pusat di pinggang kita mulai sekarang.
Gayz who will damn the bail ...
Gayz yang akan mengutuk jaminan ...
There is a grudge that will cause cruel blood.
Ada dendam yang akan menyebabkan darah kejam.
Either martyrdom or victorious.
Kemartiran atau menang.
So we'll burn Samsan's Obasi.
Jadi kita akan membakar Oban milik Samsan.
We came, after that only the angel of death will circulate in this land.
Kami datang, setelah itu hanya malaikat maut yang akan beredar di negeri ini.
[ah! ]
[ah! ]
(what is happening?)
(apa yang terjadi?)
You know I lost my chick.
Anda tahu saya kehilangan anak perempuan saya.
If you consent, I would like to crown the girl's Aygül in my mansion.
Jika Anda setuju, saya ingin memahkotai Aygül gadis itu di rumah saya.
Alişar Bey.
Alişar Bey.
Mr. Dundar.
Pak Dundar.
I am very sorry that I made you wait but ...
Saya sangat menyesal membuat saya menunggu tetapi ...
... the texts of the agreement you are curiously waiting for are ready.
... teks-teks perjanjian yang Anda tunggu-tunggu sudah siap.
Since the traitor Yannis died too ...
Karena pengkhianat Yannis meninggal juga ...
... there is no obstacle to seal the agreement.
... tidak ada halangan untuk menyegel perjanjian.
Will the agreement be made when Osman disappears?
Akankah perjanjian dibuat ketika Osman menghilang?
Mr. Dundar?
Pak Dundar?
We also speak of big, shush is small.
Kita juga berbicara tentang besar, shush kecil.
When it comes to the subject of the agreement, with my brother's duty ...
Ketika datang ke subjek perjanjian, dengan tugas saudara saya ...
...seal
... segel
is in my hands
ada di tangan saya
Dundar Bey
Dundar Bey
Princess Sofia
Putri Sofia
At one time I had seen a beautiful flower on the Caspian coast.
Pada suatu waktu saya telah melihat bunga yang indah di pantai Kaspia.
The smell is still in my nose.
Bau itu masih ada di hidungku.
Every time I see you, that flower comes to my mind.
Setiap kali saya melihat Anda, bunga itu muncul di benak saya.
And how toxic it is.
Dan betapa berbahayanya itu.
[Or to]
[Atau untuk]
Where is Salvador?
Dimana Salvador?
Where is Slavador?
Dimana Slavador?
Do not bother Osman Bey.
Jangan ganggu Osman Bey.
He will find you.
Dia akan menemukanmu.
The Yannis demon who harmed our friend found the trouble.
Setan Yannis yang melukai teman kami menemukan masalah.
Informal is the time to make our friend permanent.
Informal adalah waktu untuk menjadikan teman kita permanen.
But last time you tried to make a deal without me.
Tetapi terakhir kali Anda mencoba membuat kesepakatan tanpa saya.
And, there's no work left for you.
Dan, tidak ada pekerjaan yang tersisa untuk Anda.
Without the consent of Alişar Bey in these tupras ...
Tanpa persetujuan Alişar Bey dalam tupra ini ...
... no flowers are pierced.
... tidak ada bunga yang ditusuk.
Now...
Sekarang ...
Let's live the memory of my late husband Yorgo Pulos together.
Mari kita hidup bersama ingatan mendiang suamiku Yorgo Pulos.
Let's renew the deal.
Mari kita perbarui kesepakatan.
Let's finish the work started by Dündar Bey together.
Mari kita selesaikan pekerjaan yang dimulai oleh Dündar Bey bersama-sama.
Moreover, unlike the old agreement, Dundar Bey wanted the matter of confederation ...
Selain itu, tidak seperti perjanjian lama, Dundar Bey menginginkan masalah konfederasi ...
... added to the deal.
... ditambahkan ke dalam kesepakatan.
Are the items we want in the agreement?
Apakah barang yang kita inginkan dalam perjanjian?
There are, Dündar Bey.
Ada, Dündar Bey.
Mr. Alişar, as if you have no trust in us.
Pak Alişar, seolah-olah Anda tidak percaya pada kami.
You read the items very carefully.
Anda membaca item dengan sangat hati-hati.
Without care, there is no reputation Calosnose.
Tanpa perawatan, tidak ada reputasi Calosnose.
You will give Aybars account!
Anda akan memberikan akun Aybars!
You give!
Anda memberi!
You will be notified when they make you talk.
Anda akan diberitahu ketika mereka membuat Anda berbicara.
Storm
Boran
Hello, sir.
Halo, tuan.
My Selcan aunt is here, I have to go to the thesis.
Bibiku Selcan ada di sini, aku harus pergi ke tesis.
Take this push to our place.
Terima dorongan ini ke tempat kami.
Speak until late at night.
Bicaralah sampai larut malam.
Don't worry, sir.
Jangan khawatir, tuan.
If the snake was, the nightingale would be cut, evelAllah.
Jika seekor ular akan memiliki burung bulbul,
Samsa sergeant, you go to oban. Wait for news from me.
Sersan Samsa, Anda pergi ke oban. Tunggu kabar dari saya.
Selcan Hatun.
Selcan Hatun.
Among all these problems, this was missing.
Di antara semua masalah ini, ini tidak ada.
Thank goodness, I saw Selcan Hatun once again with the eyes of the world.
Syukurlah, aku melihat Selcan Hatun sekali lagi dengan mata dunia.
Ayse.
Ayse.
Aunt, welcome.
Bibi, selamat datang.
My beautiful daughter.
Gadis cantikku
Welcome, Selcan yenge.
Selamat datang, Selcan yenge.
I Aygül.
Aku aygul.
We enjoyed it.
Kami menikmatinya.
Welcome, Selcan Hatun.
Selamat datang, Selcan Hatun.
What it was like a Zöhre lime well swim.
Seperti apa rasanya Zöhre berenang dengan baik.
Give it a surprise, babe.
Berikan kejutan, sayang.
Thanks God.
Terima kasih Tuhan.
Where's my black-eyed Osman?
Di mana Osman bermata hitam saya?
Come on I said, you put Osman in caged tents.
Ayo kataku, kamu letakkan Osman di tenda sangkar.
The mountains of Söğüd mean that the stones have been spoken.
Pegunungan Söğüd berarti bahwa batu-batu telah diucapkan.
Across the Selcan line, all creatures are expressed ...
Melintasi garis Selcan, semua makhluk diekspresikan ...
don't you know, Zöhre?
Apakah kamu tidak tahu, Zöhre?
Come on chatter, where's my Osman?
Ayo mengobrol, di mana Osman saya?
Mr. Dundar said that a caged tent comes from him ...
Mr Dundar mengatakan bahwa tenda sangkar berasal darinya ...
... cut his own punishment.
... memotong hukumannya sendiri.
He came from him.
Dia datang darinya.
Now, where does God know?
Sekarang, di mana Tuhan tahu?
Of course, Osman knows that he could not fit in his neck even as a child.
Tentu saja, Osman tahu bahwa dia tidak bisa muat di lehernya bahkan sebagai seorang anak.
Aygül, bring me a buttermilk. My lung became dust.
Aygül, bawakan aku buttermilk. Paru-paru saya menjadi debu.
Right now, Selcan aunt.
Sekarang, bibi Selcan.
Here you go.
Di sini Anda pergi.
Here, Selcan hatun.
Di sini, Selcan hatun.
Ertuğrul You established your car in the shadow of my bey's bed.
Ertuğrul Anda mendirikan mobil Anda di bawah bayangan tempat tidur lebah saya.
But don't you know, weed doesn't end in the shadow of his bed.
Tapi tahukah Anda, gulma tidak berakhir di bayangan tempat tidurnya.
Although Dundar does not have a good place for my gentleman, we will live and thank him.
Meskipun Dundar tidak memiliki tempat yang baik untuk pria saya, kita akan hidup dan berterima kasih padanya.
May God give you and your loved ones a long life.
Semoga Tuhan memberi Anda dan orang yang Anda cintai umur panjang.
Amine.
Amin.
Our face faces the black winter, migration is not smoothed this season.
Wajah kami menghadapi musim dingin yang hitam, migrasi tidak lancar musim ini.
No, is it bad or Selcan hatun?
Tidak, apakah Hatun itu buruk atau Selcan?
God knows both the good and the bad.
Tuhan tahu yang baik dan yang buruk.
What's up? Are you afraid that we might be disturbed?
Tidak ada itu? Apakah Anda takut kami akan terganggu?
Estağfirullah.
Estağfirullah.
My concern is because of you.
Kekhawatiran saya adalah karena Anda.
There is nothing bad insha'Allah?
Tidak ada yang buruk insya Allah?
I'm tired, Zöhre.
Saya lelah, Zöhre.
My obese is tired.
Obesiku lelah.
After Gündoğdum passed to the hereafter, it was not stopped there.
Setelah Gündoğdum berlalu ke akhirat, itu tidak berhenti di situ.
Before I came, my oban will be on the way in time, insha'Allah.
Sebelum saya datang, oban saya akan segera tiba, insya Allah.
insha'Allah.
insya Allah.
Who are these wilds?
Siapakah binatang buas ini?
These are snakes.
Ini adalah ular.
Snake.
Ular.
Me too...
Aku juga ...
... I also have a trust that burdened my shoulders.
... Saya juga memiliki kepercayaan yang membebani pundak saya.
These angels are the murderers of my brother Aybars.
Malaikat-malaikat ini adalah pembunuh saudara lelaki saya Aybars.
They also have heads.
Mereka juga memiliki kepala.
I'll bring it to you, too.
Saya akan membawanya kepada Anda juga.
He's not a crap, Yannis, right?
Dia bukan omong kosong, Yannis, kan?
It's the head of the snake, I grabbed it from its tail.
Itu kepala ular, aku mengambilnya dari ekornya.
We will crush your head, evelallah.
Kami akan menghancurkan kepalamu, evelallah.
Don't worry.
Jangan khawatir.
Now...
Sekarang ...
... take your revenge beyond me, Bamsı.
... balas dendammu, Bamsı.
Although the blood flowing from them is like the water of the Alaca river ...
Meskipun darah yang mengalir dari mereka seperti air sungai Alaca ...
... guinea does not cool my pain.
... guinea tidak mendinginkan rasa sakitku.
I Uthman ...
Saya Utsman ...
You exist.
Kamu ada
I have eaten your right, Osman.
Saya sudah makan hak Anda, Osman.
I forgot Aybars, I would remember
Saya lupa Aybars, saya akan ingat
In our race ...
Dalam perlombaan kami ...
... there is no forgetting Burçin chick.
... tidak ada cewek Burçin yang lupa.
Mr. Bamsi ...
Tuan Bamsi ...
Souls!
Jiwa!
Siblings!
Saudara!
Yarenler!
Yarenler!
Today is the day when the fire inside me cools.
Hari ini adalah hari ketika api di dalam diriku mendingin.
Today...
Hari ini ...
... my martyr, Aybars
... martir saya, Aybars
is the day of revenge.
adalah hari pembalasan.
These snakes thought ...
Ular ini berpikir ...
... we forget our pain, we don't go after it.
... kita melupakan rasa sakit kita, kita tidak mengejarnya.
... we are not accountable.
... kami tidak bertanggung jawab.
But...
Tapi ...
... black Osman ...
... Osman hitam ...
... he grabbed them with his paw like an eagle and threw them in front of me.
... dia meraih mereka dengan cakarnya seperti rajawali dan melemparkannya ke hadapanku.
Now...
Sekarang ...
... me too ....
... aku juga ....
... their poisonous head was removed from their tails.
... kepala beracun mereka dikeluarkan dari ekor mereka.
(God!)
(Tuhan!)
Allahu akbar.
Allahu akbar.
(Long live my Osman!)
(Hidup Osman saya!)
(My life is Bamsı Bey!)
(Hidupku adalah Bamsı Bey!)
The day is that all the snakes trying to infiltrate the Turkish heart ...
Hari ini adalah semua ular yang mencoba menyusup ke jantung Turki ...
... is the day of cutting his head.
... adalah hari memotong kepalanya.
Day...
Hari ...
... our faith ...
... iman kita ...
... It's time to walk to the Red Apple.
... Saatnya berjalan ke Red Apple.
I am the valiant Osman of Karagöz.
Saya Osman yang gagah berani dari Karagöz.
Welcome, aunt.
Selamat datang, bibi.
I found it nice.
Saya menemukan itu bagus.
When I saw you, I saw the rest and the tolerant, my son, insha'Allah.
Ketika saya melihat Anda, saya melihat yang lain dan yang toleran, anak saya, insya Allah.
Come, let's move on to my father's bed.
Ayo, mari kita pindah ke tempat tidur ayahku.
He found Tekvur's murderer, found Aybars' murderers and brought them to the camp.
Dia menemukan pembunuh Tekvur, menemukan pembunuh Aybars dan membawa mereka ke kamp.
Osman became a waterfall flood.
Osman menjadi banjir air terjun.
I'll stop him in front of him ...
Saya akan menghentikannya di depannya ...
... or the flow will destroy us all.
... atau aliran akan menghancurkan kita semua.
The lion of his father ...
Singa ayahnya ...
... good fortune, Osman.
... semoga beruntung, Osman.
Osman...
Osman ...
... drop eyelashes over your eyes.
... letakkan bulu mata di matamu.
What's poking your mind? Say it to me.
Apa yang menyodok pikiranmu? Katakan itu padaku.
I saw you like this, my sister.
Aku melihatmu seperti ini, kakakku.
... there is no problem, alhamdulillah.
... tidak ada masalah, alhamdulillah.
Here you go.
Di sini Anda pergi.
Oh, my Osman.
Oh, Osman saya.
Thank goodness you ended.
Syukurlah Anda sudah selesai.
Kayı obaları unites.
Kayı obaları bersatu.
Day will come...
Harinya akan datang ...
... sentence Oğuz obaları will be united.
... kalimat Oğuz obaları akan disatukan.
It will be strong.
Itu akan kuat.
Hopefully, my lion.
Semoga singa saya.
God willing.
Mudah-mudahan.
I heard you went to the caravanserai?
Saya mendengar Anda pergi ke karavan?
Yeah.
Ya.
I went.
Aku pergi.
What's up?
Tidak ada itu?
Osman...
Osman ...
... where did you find this dagger?
... di mana Anda menemukan belati ini?
Has anyone caught your attention in Caravanserai?
Adakah yang menarik perhatian Anda di Caravanserai?
It did.
Itu benar.
The princess of Kulucahisar.
Putri Kulucahisar.
He came to me.
Dia mendatangi saya.
Sofia.
Sofia.
But what could Sofia have to do with this dagger, son?
Tapi apa yang bisa dilakukan Sofia dengan belati ini, Nak?
For your life ...
Untuk hidupmu ...
... they asked me to forgive someone's life.
... mereka meminta saya untuk memaafkan hidup seseorang.
What are you saying?
Apa yang kamu katakan
Sofia?
Sofia?
Yannis.
Yannis.
Who is in Yannis?
Siapa yang ada di Yannis?
We'll talk tonight, aunt.
Kami akan bicara malam ini, bibi.
I Uthman ...
Saya Utsman ...
... when I arrived in the caravanserai ...
... ketika saya tiba di karavan ...
... I saw the blessed face of Sheikh Edbali.
... Saya melihat wajah diberkati Sheikh Edbali.
What are you saying aunt?
Apa yang kamu katakan bibi?
Yeah.
Ya.
Your face shone like the moon, my lion.
Wajahmu bersinar seperti bulan, singa ku.
What's up?
Tidak ada itu?
You gave me very important news.
Anda memberi saya berita yang sangat penting.
What about her daughter?
Bagaimana dengan putrinya?
Was her daughter with you?
Apakah putrinya bersamamu?
You call the bala chick?
Anda memanggil cewek bala?
Yeah.
Ya.
Of course.
Tentu saja.
We also met him.
Kami juga bertemu dengannya.
Where did you revolt?
Di mana Anda memberontak?
I must go to the caravanserai.
Saya harus pergi ke karavan.
We have a lot of issues to talk about tonight.
Kami memiliki banyak masalah untuk dibicarakan malam ini.
My death will make them so much fun ...
Kematianku akan membuat mereka sangat menyenangkan ...
...I have never thought of that.
... saya tidak pernah berpikir.
(laughs)
(tertawa)
The Edebali ...
The Edebali ...
he will think you're dead, sir.
dia akan berpikir kau sudah mati, tuan.
Thus, it will move more comfortably.
Dengan demikian, ia akan bergerak lebih nyaman.
If it was that easy ...
Jika semudah itu ...
... I would have died already.
... Aku pasti sudah mati.
Prince Salvador.
Pangeran Salvador.
Osman...
Osman ...
... trapped, sir.
... terjebak, tuan.
Now it's time ...
Sekarang saatnya ...
... the big wolf.
... serigala besar.
I thought you would be sorry for your warriors ...
Saya pikir Anda akan menyesal pejuang Anda ...
Prince Salvador.
Pangeran Salvador.
It may upset me just to be deviated from my ideals, commander.
Mungkin membuatku kesal hanya karena menyimpang dari cita-citaku, komandan.
Is our direction clear?
Apakah arah kita jelas?
Of course it is, my moth.
Tentu saja, ngengat saya.
Our direction is immediate.
Arah kami segera.
Amenna sir.
Amenna, Tuan.
My comrades ...
Kawan-kawan saya ...
... more than being born a Muslim and being a Muslim ...
... lebih dari dilahirkan sebagai seorang Muslim dan menjadi seorang Muslim ...
... to stay Muslim.
... untuk tetap Muslim.
Let the ember be gadr us, let the ember take us from our dormitories.
Biarkan bara menjadi gadr kita, biarkan bara mengambil kita dari asrama kita.
The rose in the bush does not end, saying ignorant is not enough ...
Mawar di semak-semak tidak berakhir, mengatakan bodoh tidak cukup ...
... we will continue on our way.
... kita akan melanjutkan perjalanan kita.
We will not deviate from our direction.
Kami tidak akan menyimpang dari arah kami.
Remember, the lovers ...
Ingat, para kekasih ...
... the spiritual reward for those who do not submit to persecution ...
... imbalan spiritual bagi mereka yang tidak tunduk pada penganiayaan ...
... is honor and majesty.
... adalah kehormatan dan keagungan.
Thank you, sir.
Terima kasih tuan
Sir...
Saya sendiri.
... We hear news that Yannis was killed.
... Kami mendengar berita bahwa Yannis terbunuh.
They threw a piece of bread on the mouse ...
Mereka melemparkan sepotong roti ke mouse ...
... the awake mouse looked at the ground and the piece of bread.
... tikus yang terjaga melihat ke tanah dan sepotong roti.
He said there is something odd about this.
Dia mengatakan ada sesuatu yang aneh tentang ini.
Bread is big ...
Roti itu besar ...
... and the distance is short.
... dan jaraknya pendek.
What is your doubt, sir?
Apa keraguan Anda, tuan?
Yannis ...
Yannis ...
... big bait.
... umpan besar.
Moreover, it is thought-provoking to get out of it so easily.
Selain itu, sangat memprihatinkan untuk keluar darinya dengan mudah.
In my opinion, a girl like Sofia ...
Menurut pendapat saya, seorang gadis seperti Sofia ...
never consents to his father's execution.
tidak pernah menyetujui eksekusi ayahnya.
Their intentions are also clear.
Niat mereka juga jelas.
You know the location of the treasure ...
Anda tahu lokasi harta karun ...
... don't they know that?
... tidakkah mereka tahu itu?
They know.
Mereka tahu.
For this reason, they will throw their clamps to Osman.
Untuk alasan ini, mereka akan membuang klem mereka ke Osman.
Get in his way ...
Menghalanginya ...
... they will wish to distract you.
... mereka akan ingin mengalihkan perhatian Anda.
Akcam ...
Akcam ...
... Osman went to death?
... Osman mati?
It's not gone, sir.
Itu tidak hilang, tuan.
So his trial began with the devil.
Maka pengadilannya dimulai dengan iblis.
When he learned that you are here from the Selcan line ...
Ketika dia mengetahui bahwa Anda di sini dari garis Selcan ...
will come to your threshold, sir.
akan datang ke ambang pintu Anda, Pak.
He will want to see you.
Dia akan ingin melihatmu.
Selamun aleykum.
Selamunaleyküm.
I Aleykümselam.
Aku Aleykümselam.
Say to Edebali Osman wants to discuss an important issue, dervish.
Katakan kepada Edebali Osman ingin membahas masalah penting, darwis.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Mr. Osman!
Osman!
Honey chick.
Cewek sayang
Thank goodness, I found you.
Syukurlah, aku menemukanmu.
I was worried when he went unannounced.
Saya khawatir ketika dia pergi tanpa pemberitahuan.
Or...
Atau ...
... is your father angry with me?
... Apakah ayahmu marah padaku?
Osman Bey, who was born inside.
Osman Bey, yang lahir di dalam.
I know, I made a mistake.
Saya tahu, saya melakukan kesalahan.
I broke your heart.
Aku menghancurkan hatimu.
I came here ...
Saya datang ke sini ...
... so that I can kiss your hand and get halal.
... agar aku bisa mencium tanganmu dan mendapatkan halal.
My father, Osman Bey, does not turn away to the threshold.
Ayah saya, Osman Bey, tidak berpaling ke ambang pintu.
Both ...
Kedua ...
... sorry for what you did.
... maaf atas apa yang kamu lakukan.
He wishes to guide you.
Ia ingin membimbing Anda.
My father is praised, he is our light.
Ayah saya dipuji, dia adalah terang kita.
I wouldn't want to grieve.
Saya tidak ingin berduka.
Do you know why you broke my dad?
Apakah Anda tahu mengapa Anda menghancurkan ayah saya?
I know, Bala chick.
Saya tahu, Bala cewek.
I will fight for justice ...
Saya akan memperjuangkan keadilan ...
I tried to be justice.
Saya mencoba menjadi keadilan.
You thought right.
Anda berpikir benar.
He will be happy to come.
Dia akan senang datang.
God willing.
Mudah-mudahan.
Hopefully Bala chick.
Semoga Bala cewek.
Let me see one face ...
Biarkan saya melihat satu wajah ...
... let me get a prayer.
... biarkan aku berdoa.
I have something to say to him.
Saya ingin mengatakan sesuatu kepadanya.
Then you.
Lalu kamu.
Until my father came ...
Sampai ayahku datang ...
... you are Mr. Osman.
... Anda adalah Tn. Osman.
We saw Selcan aunt.
Kami melihat bibi Selcan.
I know.
Aku tahu.
Thanks to him I found you.
Berkat dia aku menemukanmu.
I was so scared that I would never see you again, Bala chick.
Saya sangat takut bahwa saya tidak akan pernah melihat Anda lagi, Bala cewek.
To ask you ...
Untuk bertanya ...
... I will send my aunt Selcan to the father.
... Aku akan mengirim bibiku Selcan ke ayah.
Why did your face drop?
Mengapa wajahmu jatuh?
Selamun aleykum.
Selamunaleyküm.
Hello, dervish.
Halo, darwis.
You are welcome, Mr. Osman.
Sama-sama, Tuan Osman.
Nice, we saw.
Bagus, kami melihat.
I wish to see Edebali.
Saya ingin melihat Edebali.
Sir is not available, Osman.
Pak tidak tersedia, Osman.
Does he know it's important?
Apakah dia tahu itu penting?
Knows.
Dia tahu.
Let me see it.
Biarkan saya melihatnya.
Mr. Osman!
Osman!
Be patient.
Bersabarlah.
Patience is the door of the client. You know.
Kesabaran adalah pintu klien. Anda tahu.
Your father closed the door to the face of the woman standing on the brink, Bala chick.
Ayahmu menutup pintu ke wajah wanita yang berdiri di tepi jurang, Bala cewek.
Now you...
Sekarang kamu ...
... are you angry with the hand that you held out?
... Apakah Anda marah dengan tangan yang Anda pegang?
Or are you angry with extending the hand that cannot be held?
Atau apakah Anda marah dengan mengulurkan tangan yang tidak bisa dipegang?
I did all the mistakes and suffering now.
Saya membuatnya sendiri, saya menemukannya sendiri.
A hillock on the road overwhelmed you ...
Sebuah bukit kecil di jalan membuat Anda kewalahan ...
but there are hundreds of mountains in front of you.
tetapi ada ratusan gunung di depan Anda.
Surrendering doesn't work for me, Bala chick.
Menyerah tidak bekerja untukku, Bala cewek.
Then you will have to be patient.
Maka Anda harus bersabar.
Is our glaze cube full?
Apakah glaze cube kami penuh?
He must have had a little fever that is leaking water, sir.
Dia pasti mengalami sedikit demam yaitu air bocor, Pak.
Then it is necessary to waste.
Maka perlu dibuang.
Elbet my father knows Osman.
Elbet, ayahku kenal Osman.
I know.
Aku tahu.
It is difficult to wait at the Vuslat gate.
Sulit menunggu di gerbang Vuslat.
I...
Saya ...
... going to wait ...
... akan menunggu ...
I wait until my last breath.
Saya menunggu sampai nafas terakhir saya.
As long as you wait? Let me know him.
Selama kamu menunggu? Biarkan aku kenal dia.
I'll be your companion on my father's path.
Aku akan menjadi temanmu di jalan ayahku.
For this reason, I wait until my last breath.
Untuk alasan ini, saya menunggu sampai nafas terakhir saya.
However, the road looks pretty difficult. You know.
Namun, jalannya terlihat cukup sulit. Anda tahu.
If I lose my breath ...
Jika saya kehilangan nafas ...
... you breathe.
... kamu bernafas.
As long as...
Selama ...
... let me know that I have a companion on this road.
... beri tahu saya bahwa saya memiliki teman di jalan ini.
Then keep your heart fresh.
Kemudian jaga agar hatimu tetap segar.
Waiting for a lifetime is companionship ...
Menunggu seumur hidup adalah persahabatan ...
... I'll wait.
... Aku akan menunggu.
I'll be back, Bala chick.
Saya akan kembali, Bala cewek.
You were just going to say something to me.
Anda hanya akan mengatakan sesuatu kepada saya.
Aygül hatun ...
Aygül hatun ...
What happened to Aygül?
Apa yang terjadi dengan Aygül?
He came to me when he was a guest in his room.
Dia datang kepada saya ketika dia seorang tamu di kamarnya.
Obi field of ...
bidang Obi dari ...
... he said you were in trouble too.
... dia bilang kau juga dalam masalah.
He warned me.
Dia memperingatkan saya.
There is no need to get angry, Mr. Osman.
Tidak perlu marah, Pak Osman.
He is of your blood, of life.
Dia adalah darahmu, hidup.
What happens to Aygül?
Apa yang terjadi pada Aygül?
It's not you, me, Osman.
Bukan kamu, aku, Osman.
So what?
Jadi apa
You have the heart of the Aygül line.
Anda memiliki hati di garis Aygül.
You know my heart is with you, Bala hat.
Kau tahu hatiku bersamamu, topi Bala.
Leave the Aygül issue to me.
Serahkan masalah Aygül kepada saya.
Not that...
Namun ...
... I didn't know that I had fallen over to Edebali to not want to see me.
... Saya tidak tahu bahwa saya telah jatuh ke Edebali untuk tidak ingin melihat saya.
I will wait patiently.
Saya akan menunggu dengan sabar.
Excuse me, Bala chick.
Maaf, Bala cewek.
[Master is not available, Osman.]
[Master tidak tersedia, Osman.]
[Patience.]
[Kesabaran.]
[Patience is the door of the child, you know.]
[Kesabaran adalah pintu anak, kau tahu.]
Come on.
Ayo
Come sit down like this.
Duduklah seperti ini.
Come.
Ayo.
There are important things your father will talk about, girl.
Ada hal penting yang akan dibicarakan ayahmu, nona.
Listen with life.
Dengarkan dengan hidup.
My daughter...
Putri saya ...
... at our ceremony ...
... di upacara kami ...
... the daughter is the crown.
... putrinya adalah mahkota.
Because he...
Karena dia ...
... is a guest who leaves when the time comes.
... adalah tamu yang pergi ketika saatnya tiba.
It's time for you, girl.
Sudah waktunya untukmu, gadis.
I would like ...
Saya ingin ...
... not on the hillside ...
... tidak di lereng bukit ...
... put it in a pure place.
... letakkan di tempat yang murni.
Kadir, be a valuable person.
Kadir, jadilah orang yang berharga.
Today...
Hari ini ...
... in Kulucahisar, we were with Alişar bey.
... di Kulucahisar, kami bersama Alişar bey.
You know...
Anda tahu ...
... his chick passed away.
... ceweknya meninggal.
As a spouse, he sees you well.
Sebagai pasangan, dia melihatmu dengan baik.
He asked me about his offer ...
Dia bertanya tentang tawarannya ...
I will ask you too, girl.
Aku juga akan bertanya padamu, nona.
Is there a consent?
Apakah ada persetujuan?
Your father asks you, my daughter.
Ayahmu bertanya padamu, putriku.
As you see fit, dad.
Sesuai keinginan Anda, ayah.
My daughter...
Putri saya ...
... your mouth says another, your eyes speak another.
... mulutmu mengatakan yang lain, matamu berbicara yang lain.
Now you...
Sekarang kamu ...
... stay a little alone ...
... tinggal sedikit sendirian ...
... you should think really.
... kamu harus berpikir kok.
Well.
Nah.
Girl mind, goose mind Dündar.
Pikiran gadis, angsa pikiran Dündar.
Will it be left alone with such an important decision?
Apakah akan dibiarkan sendiri dengan keputusan penting seperti itu?
The rose of the garden without consent, chick.
Mawar taman tanpa persetujuan, cewek.
My daughter...
Putriku ...
... not for sale at the new market stall.
... tidak dijual di kios pasar baru.
Leave...
Jatuhkan ...
... his own decision ...
... keputusannya sendiri ...
... let it be your own.
... biarkan itu menjadi milikmu.
Look at the fire of those candles ...
Lihatlah api lilin-lilin itu ...
... Kalanos.
... Kalanos.
How timid and how they tremble.
Bagaimana malu-malu dan bagaimana mereka gemetar.
If I blow, they will go out.
Jika saya meniup, mereka akan keluar.
Our dreams will come true, darling.
Mimpi kita akan menjadi kenyataan, sayang.
We will come together from the right of the Turks.
Kami akan datang bersama dari kanan Turki.
Master Yannis will show us the way.
Tuan Yannis akan menunjukkan jalannya.
We are on that road ...
Kami berada di jalan itu ...
... we will walk hand in hand.
... kita akan berjalan beriringan.
As you look at me like this ...
Ketika Anda melihat saya seperti ini ...
... as the fire of love burns in our hearts
... Seperti api cinta membakar di hati kita
... we have enough, Sofia.
... kita sudah cukup, Sofia.
Why did this come?
Mengapa ini terjadi?
The migration was flat, they would settle down.
Migrasi itu datar, mereka akan tenang.
Fifty tents ...
Lima puluh tenda ...
five hundred throats chick.
lima ratus tenggorokan cewek.
Anyway, our two sides don't come together.
Ngomong-ngomong, kedua pihak kita tidak bertemu.
Now...
Sekarang ...
... and deal with them.
... dan berurusan dengan mereka.
As soon as he came, he asked Osman.
Begitu dia datang, dia bertanya pada Osman.
There is no need to tell you Selcan hat.
Tidak perlu memberi tahu Anda topi Selcan.
Don't take your eyes off.
Jangan mengalihkan pandangan Anda.
Welcome, aunt.
Selamat datang, bibi.
I found it nice, Mr. Dundar.
Saya merasa baik, Pak Dundar.
Here you go ...
Di sini Anda pergi ...
... these preparations were made for you.
... persiapan ini dibuat untukmu.
God bless you.
Tuhan memberkatimu
The brother fought with the brother ...
Saudaranya berkelahi dengan saudara ...
... he believed in eblehte.
... dia percaya pada eblehte.
Batu ...
Batu ...
...Osman.
... Osman.
Say, is it true?
Katakan, apakah itu benar?
Does our quarrel have a brother fight?
Apakah pertengkaran kita membuat saudara kita bertengkar?
No, aunt.
Tidak, bibi.
Honestly, not.
Jujur saja, tidak.
Not that...
Namun ...
Osman ruled without listening to me.
Osman memerintah tanpa mendengarkan saya.
I Baturina ...
Saya Baturina ...
... I was a sky-eyed valiant.
... Aku adalah seorang pemberani bermata langit.
Let's ask Osman.
Mari kita tanyakan pada Osman.
My aunt ...
bibi saya ...
... let's never open this matter.
... jangan pernah membuka masalah ini.
Don't let our taste go unnoticed.
Jangan biarkan selera kita luput dari perhatian.
My Day ...
Hari saya ...
...My sun.
... Surya.
The trouble in the room is not by smoking ...
Masalah di kamar bukan dengan merokok ...
... it is solved by going to it.
... diselesaikan dengan pergi ke sana.
This matter is as fresh as Batur's wound, Selcan hatun.
Hal ini sama segar dengan luka Batur, Selcan hatun.
If you scratch it will bleed.
Jika Anda menggaruknya akan berdarah.
I say scratching.
Saya katakan menggaruk.
We came from the wake of Saime Ana, Zöhre chick.
Kami datang dari bangun dari Saime Ana, Zöhre cewek.
I saw three gentlemen in my life.
Saya melihat tiga pria dalam hidup saya.
I would say the wound is not to bleed ...
Saya akan mengatakan lukanya tidak berdarah ...
I want to treat.
Saya ingin mengobati.
Osman...
Osman ...
Is Batur right?
Apakah Batur benar?
He grabbed me when I never expected.
Dia meraihku ketika aku tidak pernah berharap.
I wouldn't expect this from Osman.
Saya tidak akan mengharapkan ini dari Osman.
I Uthman ...
Saya Utsman ...
... is it true what Batur said?
... benarkah yang dikatakan Batur?
Toy Osmancık.
Toy Osmancik.
Ham Osmancık.
Ham Osmancık.
Who is thesis ...
Siapa tesis ...
... his hard work will be less.
... kerja kerasnya akan kurang.
Know this like this.
Ketahui ini seperti ini.
It is true, aunt.
Memang benar, bibi.
It is not error free ...
Ini bukan bebas kesalahan ...
...not that...
... namun ...
I was impulsive.
Saya impulsif.
Osman.
Osman.
I was a dark-eyed, wolf-eyed brave.
Saya seorang pemberani bermata gelap, bermata serigala.
The mountain stone breaks the wind, and the brotherhood spoils.
Batu gunung menghancurkan angin, dan persaudaraan rampasan.
I am a mountain-like son ...
Saya seorang anak seperti gunung ...
... and left my brave Gündoğdu.
... dan meninggalkan Gündoğdu pemberani saya.
I have no branch to hold on to you, no one, no one.
Saya tidak punya cabang untuk Anda pegang, tidak ada, tidak ada.
If you stand apart like this ...
Jika Anda berdiri terpisah seperti ini ...
... which branch will I hold?
... cabang mana yang akan saya pegang?
The nation of Oğuz is the demote of Dem Korkut.
Bangsa Oğuz adalah demote Dem Korkut.
Haram mixes zade, halal zade is reconciled.
Haram mencampur zade, zade halal direkonsiliasi.
Come on, hug each other.
Ayo, saling berpelukan.
You're done.
Anda sudah selesai.
Meyyit pan, let the toy air.
Meyyit panci, biarkan mainannya mengudara.
Forgive me.
Halal, hak Anda.
It is lawful.
Adalah sah.
Halal your right, his son.
Halal hakmu, putranya.
Hay, thank you.
Hay, terima kasih.
My aunt ...
bibi saya ...
.... you came with compassion.
.... Anda datang dengan belas kasih.
May you be shaad.
Semoga Anda shaad.
Your room needed a main breath.
Kamar Anda membutuhkan napas utama.
On a mother's lap ...
Di pangkuan seorang ibu ...
... to the main kindness.
... untuk kebaikan utama.
My daughter...
Putri saya ...
... I see you very stagnant.
... saya melihat Anda sangat stagnan.
Come on.
Ayo
I hope it's good.
Tidak, saya harap.
I'm fine, dad.
Saya baik-baik saja, ayah.
I'm fine ...
Aku baik-baik ...
... I'm getting a little tired.
... Aku mulai sedikit lelah.
What is it that strikes my light into darkness?
Apa yang membuat terang saya menjadi gelap?
Let's learn also.
Mari belajar juga.
Our father.
Ayah kita
We are gadget wherever we go.
Kami adalah gadget ke mana pun kami pergi.
Games are being played behind us, in front of us.
Permainan sedang dimainkan di belakang kami, di depan kami.
I wonder, how will we leave?
Saya bertanya-tanya, bagaimana kita akan pergi?
He thinks that ...
Dia berpikir bahwa ...
... I would get mad at it.
... Aku akan marah karenanya.
This was the case with your late mother Ulduz.
Ini adalah kasus dengan almarhum ibumu, Ulduz.
Something on my head is installed in the corner ...
Sesuatu di kepalaku dipasang di sudut ...
... would eat himself inside.
... akan makan sendiri di dalam.
My daughter...
Putri saya ...
... Balaam.
... Bileam.
It is not for the shrinker, but for your heart.
Ini bukan untuk menyusut, tetapi untuk hatimu.
The son of the person was folk from the blood clot, but ...
Putra orang tersebut adalah orang dari gumpalan darah, tetapi ...
... thankfully wholeheartedly.
... syukurlah sepenuh hati.
The body is a mother-of-pearl, and the heart is a pearl.
Tubuh adalah ibu dari mutiara, dan hati adalah mutiara.
Ten is an envelope, and the heart is a saving.
Sepuluh adalah sebuah amplop, dan hati adalah tabungan.
Heart...
Hati ...
... is an immense land of plums, girl.
... adalah negeri besar buah plum, gadis.
It is like a transfer that contains all healing.
Itu seperti transfer yang berisi semua penyembuhan.
If you find justice in the heart ...
Jika Anda menemukan keadilan di hati ...
.... you conscience.
.... hati nurani Anda.
If you find science in the heart ...
Jika Anda menemukan sains di hati ...
... you will be wise.
... kamu akan menjadi bijaksana.
If you find compassion in the heart ...
Jika Anda menemukan kasih sayang di hati ...
... you will have mercy.
... kamu akan berbelas kasihan.
If you find love in the heart ...
Jika Anda menemukan cinta di hati ...
... serve.
... melayani.
The two world suns, as our Messenger of Allah commanded ...
Dua dunia berjemur, seperti yang diperintahkan Utusan Allah ...
... "If our heart is strong, it will be solid in every business."
... "Jika hati kita kuat, itu akan solid dalam setiap bisnis."
But...
Namun ...
... it shouldn't have been this.
... seharusnya bukan ini.
How long have you been worrying about yourself, for us, Bala hat?
Sudah berapa lama Anda mengkhawatirkan diri sendiri, bagi kami, topi Bala?
His problem is his ...
Masalahnya adalah ...
... as much trouble as the world.
... masalah sebanyak dunia.
A person is as human as his problem.
Seseorang adalah manusia seperti masalahnya.
It is as big as trouble.
Itu sama besarnya dengan masalah.
Besides the suffering of the Islamic world ...
Selain penderitaan dunia Islam ...
... is our concern?
... Apakah perhatian kita?
One day, if your heart is troubled by all humanity ...
Suatu hari, jika hatimu terganggu oleh seluruh umat manusia ...
I hope our salvation was then.
Saya berharap keselamatan kita saat itu.
May Allah make our hearts clean.
Semoga Allah membuat hati kita bersih.
May Allah make our trouble great.
Semoga Allah membuat masalah kita hebat.
It is great that the devil does not invade our hearts.
Sangat bagus bahwa iblis tidak menyerang hati kita.
May it be great that our hearts should not be lost.
Semoga luar biasa bahwa hati kita tidak akan hilang.
Amine.
Amin.
Don't talk until my heart cools down!
Jangan bicara sampai hatiku menjadi dingin!
Do not!
Tidak!
I will start with your fingers first.
Saya akan mulai dengan jari Anda terlebih dahulu.
Now I will cut the eyelids.
Sekarang saya akan memotong kelopak mata.
Next, I will split your eyes into salt.
Selanjutnya, saya akan membelah mata Anda menjadi garam.
Brother, stop.
Saudaraku, berhenti.
Boğaç, let go.
Boga, lepaskan.
Stop, bro, stop!
Stop, bro, stop!
Leave a bull!
Tinggalkan seekor banteng!
Leave!
Jatuhkan!
I will talk.
Aku akan bicara.
I will say.
Aku akan mengatakan.
I will say everything.
Saya akan mengatakan segalanya.
Narrative.
Narasi.
Tell me, die easily.
Katakan padaku, mati dengan mudah.
I'll tell you.
Aku akan memberitahu Anda.
I will tell you everything.
Saya akan menceritakan semuanya.
Just don't give it to me.
Tapi jangan berikan itu padaku.
Salvador will overwhelm Samsa's hat tomorrow.
Salvador akan membanjiri topi Samsa besok.
They will meet their men in the caravanserai.
Mereka akan bertemu orang-orang mereka di karavan.
Well ...
Baiklah ...
... how will we recognize that shroud?
... bagaimana kita akan mengenali kain kafan itu?
There is a big sign behind his head.
Ada tanda besar di belakang kepalanya.
Gamtural is!
Gamtural adalah!
Wait here, brother.
Tunggu disini, saudara.
I will inform our brain.
Saya akan memberi tahu otak kita.
Lets!
Ayo!
Ertuğrul the day my husband brought your late mother to the oba ...
Ertuğrul hari suamiku membawa almarhum ibumu ke oba ...
... yesterday I remember son.
... kemarin aku ingat nak.
They had survived many badgoods.
Mereka telah selamat dari banyak hal buruk.
Not only did he come to his father, but to his late mother because he came to Oba.
Bukan saja dia datang ke ayahnya, tetapi juga ke almarhum ibunya karena dia datang ke Oba.
Oh, rest in the light, Halimem.
Oh, istirahatlah dalam terang, Halimem.
He faced everything, to everyone.
Dia menghadapi segalanya, untuk semua orang.
Even me.
Bahkan saya.
I used to say that you would follow your father's path.
Saya dulu mengatakan bahwa Anda akan mengikuti jalan ayahmu.
You gave me my word, son.
Anda memberi saya kata-kata saya, Nak.
You will be able to overcome the devils and evil of that devil called Yannis, insha'Allah.
Anda akan dapat mengatasi iblis dan iblis iblis bernama Yannis, insyaAllah.
You don't worry, aunt.
Anda tidak khawatir, bibi.
So, I will come to you from that devil.
Jadi, saya akan datang kepada Anda dari iblis itu.
I know.
Aku tahu.
Say, well.
Katakan, baik.
What do you wish from your aunt?
Apa yang kamu inginkan dari bibimu?
I have a heart in the line of Bala, aunt.
Saya memiliki hati di garis Bala, bibi.
Your eyes shout out, son.
Matamu berteriak, nak.
Even when he speaks his name, your eyes sparkle.
Bahkan ketika dia menyebutkan namanya, mata Anda berbinar.
Well, well.
Baik, baik.
What is your murad from me?
Apa murad Anda dari saya?
I want you to arrive at Edebali tomorrow.
Saya ingin Anda tiba di Edebali besok.
Osm me.
Osm saya.
I wish you to ask Bala's hat by order of Allah, aunt.
Saya berharap Anda meminta topi Bala atas perintah Allah, bibi.
Thank goodness we have seen these days too.
Syukurlah kita telah melihat hari ini juga.
Why would you send me while your father is standing, son?
Mengapa kamu mengirim saya ketika ayahmu berdiri, Nak?
My father's path is long, aunt.
Jalan ayahku panjang, bibi.
I don't know when he will be back to our obese.
Saya tidak tahu kapan dia akan kembali ke obesitas kami.
Both ...
Kedua ...
I don't have patience.
Saya tidak punya kesabaran.
When my father comes, we have a wedding.
Ketika ayah saya datang, kami memiliki pernikahan.
Both ...
Kedua ...
... I have broken the heart of Edebali.
... Saya telah menghancurkan hati Edebali.
I got into situations that it couldn't suit me.
Saya masuk ke situasi yang tidak cocok untuk saya.
He warned me.
Dia memperingatkan saya.
However, I realized late, aunt.
Namun, saya sadar terlambat, bibi.
Uncle ...
Paman ...
... will your son fall for me while your uncle is standing?
... akankah anakmu jatuh cinta padaku saat pamanmu berdiri?
My uncle...
Paman saya ...
... dad is half aunt.
... ayah setengah bibi.
Not that...
Namun ...
...you are my mother.
... kamu adalah ibuku.
Oh, I'm the victim.
Oh, aku korbannya.
What is the glory of Dundar when my mother is standing?
Apa kemuliaan Dundar ketika ibu saya berdiri?
You don't worry.
Kamu tidak khawatir
Tomorrow I will go to that blessed man's door at thesis time.
Besok saya akan pergi ke pintu pria yang diberkati itu pada saat tesis.
Thank you, aunt.
Terima kasih, bibi.
There is another matter, aunt.
Ada masalah lain, bibi.
Say, well.
Katakan, baik.
Aygul.
Aygul.
Your father closed the door to the face of the woman standing on the verge, Bala hat.
Ayahmu menutup pintu ke wajah wanita yang berdiri di ambang, topi Bala.
Love and mercy is a river in man Bala.
Cinta dan kasih sayang adalah sungai dalam diri manusia Bala.
If it flows strong, evil cannot hold on.
Jika mengalir kuat, kejahatan tidak bisa bertahan.
Osman Beyde is like a river.
Osman Beyde seperti sungai.
Thank God, both love and compassion are strong.
Alhamdulillah, cinta dan kasih sayang itu kuat.
But a lot of chopper.
Tapi banyak helikopter.
Impatient.
The TEZCANLI.
The Diddetl.
The Diddetl.
He said he would walk to his last breath in your companionship.
Dia mengatakan dia akan berjalan ke napas terakhirnya dalam persahabatanmu.
Don't you believe it?
Apakah kamu tidak mempercayainya?
I believe him to believe.
Saya percaya dia percaya.
At that time?
Lalu?
My father left Osman on the edge of the cliff.
Ayah saya meninggalkan Osman di tepi tebing.
I am afraid that he will turn his eyes on the cliff, not on the road.
Saya takut dia akan mengalihkan pandangan ke tebing, bukan di jalan.
Mr. Osman!
Osman!
Sabıred Basin.
Sabıred Basin.
Patience is the door of the child, you know.
Kesabaran adalah pintu anak, Anda tahu.
Osman.
Osman.
Suddenly Osman, holding on fire like a flame of flame.
Tiba-tiba Osman, memegang api seperti nyala api.
Osmancik.
Osmancik.
We just walk to you when you walk ....
Kami hanya berjalan ke Anda ketika Anda berjalan ....
... laugh when you smile ...
... tertawa ketika kamu tersenyum ...
... when you resist the persecution, let's stand patience and let the people see the state.
... ketika Anda menentang penganiayaan, mari kita bersabar dan biarkan orang melihat negara.
what do you do?
apa yang kamu lakukan
Toy Osmancık.
Toy Osmancik.
Ham Osmancık.
Ham Osmancık.
The hard work of a person with a thesis is also low.
Kerja keras seseorang dengan tesis juga rendah.
Is there any destim, sir?
Apakah ada tujuan, tuan?
You're coming.
Anda datang.
Storm?
Bora?
What are you doing here?
Apa yang kamu lakukan disini
Where's the canteen?
Dimana kantinnya?
I left it on the road, sir.
Saya meninggalkannya di jalan, Pak.
Why is that?
Mengapa?
Why did you come?
Kenapa kamu datang?
Sir said he spoke.
Pak berkata dia berbicara.
Samsa would raid his brain obes, the Salvadoran shroud.
Samsa akan menyerbu otaknya, kain kafan Salvador.
We couldn't leave you alone.
Kami tidak bisa meninggalkanmu sendirian.
Wow they are unbelievers.
Wow mereka orang-orang kafir.
Samsa sergeant huh?
Sersan Samsa ya?
I would be if I don't take their lungs out and throw them into the pus.
Aku akan jadi jika aku tidak mengambil paru-paru mereka dan membuangnya ke nanah.
I alps!
Alpen Saya!
Let's get to the osa of Samsa sergeant.
Mari kita pergi ke sersan Samsa sersan.
The day is the account day.
Hari itu adalah hari akun.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Thank you sir.
Terima kasih tuan
Over the years...
Selama bertahun-tahun ...
... kayı obasi has also changed, Aybüke.
... kayı obasi juga telah berubah, Aybüke.
It was both big and big.
Itu besar dan besar.
It grew in trouble as it grew.
Tumbuh dalam kesulitan saat tumbuh.
We are in the middle of these troubles, ma'am.
Kami berada di tengah-tengah masalah ini, Bu.
We came across precise time.
Kami menemukan waktu yang tepat.
What did he get in the eye?
Apa yang dimilikinya?
Zöhre chick.
Zohre cewek.
As if he was not very happy with our development.
Seolah dia tidak terlalu senang dengan perkembangan kita.
Why are you happy?
Kenapa kamu senang
When he thinks, he plays a horse that has dropped his nephew to uncle and brother to brother.
Ketika dia berpikir, dia memainkan kuda yang telah menjatuhkan keponakannya ke paman dan kakak laki-laki.
They left my Osman alone.
Mereka meninggalkan Osman saya sendiri.
He knows that I love you as my son.
Dia tahu bahwa aku mencintaimu sebagai anakku.
He is concerned that I have come now.
Dia khawatir bahwa saya telah datang sekarang.
Behind the gaze of the Zöhre line lies a well of grudge.
Di belakang tatapan garis Zöhre terletak sebuah sumur dendam.
Don't you touch a gadget?
Apakah kamu tidak menyentuh gadget?
Dundar brainbed is what the Zöhre line sees.
Dundar berpikiran adalah apa yang garis Zöhre lihat.
What I see is three cycles, three cycles and three major migrations.
Apa yang saya lihat adalah tiga siklus, tiga siklus dan tiga migrasi besar.
I have not bleached this hair for nothing.
Saya belum memutihkan rambut ini untuk apa-apa.
His verdict only passes to new adolescents.
Putusannya hanya diteruskan ke remaja baru.
Not a plane like me.
Bukan pesawat seperti saya.
Archers!
Pemanah!
Shoot me.
Tembak aku.
The martyrdom is closer to us than ever before.
Kemartiran lebih dekat dengan kita daripada sebelumnya.
I don't look at the tears of the mistake, so you know this.
Saya tidak melihat air mata kesalahan, jadi Anda tahu ini.
For a massive ceng ...
Untuk ceng besar ...
... for a while we have given raids to the people.
... untuk sementara kami telah melakukan penggerebekan kepada orang-orang.
The informal order has changed.
Urutan informal telah berubah.
After that, we will protect our land, our obes, our honor.
Setelah itu, kita akan melindungi tanah kita, obesitas kita, kehormatan kita.
Gentlemen at the head of the Turkish oba ...
Tuan-tuan di kepala oba Turki ...
is in heedlessness and signification.
ada dalam kelalaian dan makna.
Ceng will go and crash into the keel of the shroud.
Ceng akan pergi dan menabrak lunas kafan itu.
Those who do not get their heads on ten times before reaching the martyrdom ...
Mereka yang tidak mendapatkan kepala mereka sepuluh kali sebelum mencapai kemartiran ...
... there is no fame in my eyes.
... tidak ada ketenaran di mataku.
I wouldn't leave your collar in the other world.
Aku tidak akan meninggalkan kerahmu di dunia lain.
Is that clear?
Apakah itu jelas?
Thank you, sir!
Terima kasih tuan
Everyone knows what to do.
Semua orang tahu apa yang harus dilakukan.
The arrow thrown is three things that are not returned.
Panah yang dilemparkan adalah tiga hal yang tidak dikembalikan.
We will finish this job today.
Kami akan menyelesaikan pekerjaan ini hari ini.
We have a single arrow on the quiver!
Kami memiliki panah tunggal di quiver!
We shot, we shot.
Kami menembak, kami menembak.
We couldn't hit it, we would get a troubled enemy, which in turn ...
Kami tidak bisa mengenai itu, kami akan mendapatkan musuh yang bermasalah, yang pada gilirannya ...
... leads to sleepless nights.
... menyebabkan malam tanpa tidur.
Did you understand me!
Apakah kamu mengerti saya!
No, Selcan hatun.
Tidak, Selcan hatun.
Did something important happen?
Apakah sesuatu yang penting terjadi?
I came to talk about Aygül hatun.
Saya datang untuk berbicara tentang Aygül hatun.
I will speak straight without bending and talking.
Saya akan berbicara dengan lurus tanpa membungkuk dan berbicara.
Have you ever bent and twisted?
Pernahkah Anda membungkuk dan memutar?
It did not.
Ini tidak.
What happened to my daughter?
Apa yang terjadi pada putri saya?
I know that Aygül has a heart in Osman.
Saya tahu bahwa Aygül memiliki hati di Osman.
Where did you hear this?
Di mana Anda mendengar ini?
Now I see it in your eyes.
Sekarang saya melihatnya di mata Anda.
So I say right.
Jadi saya katakan benar.
Now let me leave my eyes.
Sekarang biarkan aku pergi dari mataku.
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu
Another chick lies in Osman's heart, Zöhre.
Cewek lain terletak di hati Osman, Zöhre.
Osman's heart in Edebali's daughter ...
Hati Osman pada putri Edebali ...
... me and my daughter, we know.
... saya dan putri saya, kami tahu.
What is it to me?
Apa urusan saya?
What about my daughter from this?
Bagaimana dengan putri saya dari ini?
If so, why did Aygül threaten the Bala woman then?
Jika demikian, mengapa Aygül mengancam wanita Bala itu?
He said we don't want you around here, you put our obesity in danger.
Dia mengatakan kami tidak ingin kamu di sini, kamu menempatkan obesitas kami dalam bahaya.
My daughter says right.
Putriku berkata benar.
But not because he has a heart in Osman.
Tapi bukan karena dia punya hati di Osman.
For that chick and her father ...
Untuk cewek itu dan ayahnya ...
He said he knew he would bring trouble.
Dia bilang dia tahu dia akan membawa masalah.
Both ...
Kedua ...
... Aygül's heart is in Alişar bey.
... Jantung Aygül ada di Alişar bey.
Alışar bey with the order of Allah ...
Alışar bey dengan perintah Allah ...
... Dundar asked my daughter for my daughter.
... Dundar meminta putriku untuk putriku.
This matter is over here.
Masalah ini ada di sini.
I'm glad about that.
Saya senang tentang itu.
God bless both of them.
Tuhan memberkati mereka berdua.
Amine.
Amin.
Obviously, things have accumulated in Oba.
Jelas, banyak hal telah terakumulasi di Oba, Zöhre.
I'll go and get the job done.
Saya akan pergi dan menyelesaikan pekerjaan.
[Sword sound.]
[Suara pedang.]
I heard you were calling me Osman.
Saya mendengar Anda memanggil saya Osman.
You were looking for the killer of Aybars, whom I lay down.
Anda mencari pembunuh Aybars, yang saya baringkan.
Come on, here I am.
Ayo, inilah aku.
Salvador.
Salvador.
Come on, let's see your account from man to man.
Ayo, mari kita lihat akun Anda dari pria ke pria.
When did you meet me as a man, Salvador?
Kapan Anda bertemu saya sebagai pria, Salvador?
Is bravery in the tongue of pusat?
Apakah keberanian ada di lidah pusat?
How many men did you take for an Alp?
Berapa banyak pria yang Anda ambil untuk Alp?
Or did you think I would forget this?
Atau apakah Anda pikir saya akan melupakan ini?
Now, you fell into my ambush.
Sekarang, Anda jatuh ke penyergapan saya.
With us, until the soil is full of blood ...
Bersama kami, sampai tanah penuh darah ...
... the fire of revenge does not go out.
... api balas dendam tidak padam.
There's no death to you until you fill your carrion.
Tidak ada kematian bagi Anda sampai Anda mengisi bangkai Anda.
Come on, God!
Ayo, Tuhan!
Appreciate Allah!
Hargai Allah!
Attack!
Menyerang!
Alps!
Alpen!
Erkut!
Erkut!
My brother!
Adikku!
If you don't want the Alps to die, throw your sword at Osman.
Jika Anda tidak ingin Alpen mati, lemparkan pedang Anda ke Osman.
I will not say this once again.
Saya tidak akan mengatakan ini sekali lagi.
Bey.
Bey.
Right.
Benar.
Erkut.
Erkut.
You called me mom.
Anda memanggil saya ibu.
Come on girl.
Ayo gadis.
Sit down I have something to say to you.
Duduk, aku punya sesuatu untuk dikatakan kepadamu.
I wanted to talk to you about Mr. Alişar.
Saya ingin berbicara dengan Anda tentang Tn. Alişar.
Your father won't let you marry him without your consent
Ayahmu tidak akan membiarkanmu menikah dengannya tanpa persetujuanmu
... you know that too.
... kamu juga tahu itu.
However, you have to marry Alişar bey Aygül.
Namun, Anda harus menikahi Alişar bey Aygül.
Your father ...
Ayahmu ...
...our
... kami
... obama our
... obama kami
... and even the fortune of your brother Batur depends on your decision.
... dan bahkan kekayaan saudaramu Batur tergantung pada keputusanmu.
What do you say mom?
Apa yang kamu katakan ibu?
What good?
Apa bagus
I'm your father's brothers.
Saya saudara ayahmu.
Mom, do you know what you're saying?
Bu, apakah Anda tahu apa yang Anda katakan?
Look girl.
Lihat gadis
I'm a healer.
Saya seorang tabib.
Ertuğrul Bey has been sick for a long time.
Ertuğrul Bey sudah lama sakit.
He hides it from everyone.
Dia menyembunyikannya dari semua orang.
I knew it, but I was silent.
Aku tahu itu, tapi aku diam.
When the time comes, your father will be opened to the road.
Ketika saatnya tiba, ayahmu akan terbuka ke jalan.
So what does this have to do with me, mom?
Jadi apa hubungannya ini denganku, bu?
Don't you know how vindictive Osman is?
Apa kau tidak tahu seberapa dendamnya Osman?
After all this, Osman will not forgive your father or brother.
Setelah semua ini, Osman tidak akan memaafkan ayah atau kakakmu.
If Beylik is not your father, Osman will sooner than later.
Jika Beylik bukan ayahmu, Osman akan lebih cepat daripada nanti.
Nobody can prevent this.
Tidak ada yang bisa mencegah ini.
Except for Alişar bey.
Kecuali untuk Alişar bey.
Did you understand me?
Apakah kamu mengerti saya?
I prepared you a blood feast, Osman.
Saya menyiapkan Anda pesta darah, Osman.
Even you will not be saved.
Bahkan kamu tidak akan diselamatkan.
No!
Tidak ada!
Where's the literary?
Di mana sastra?
Osman Bey, do not say anything to this voyage.
Osman Bey, jangan katakan apa pun tentang perjalanan ini.
Iron bending.
Besi lentur.
My dear victim.
Korban sayangku.
Iron bending!
Besi lentur!
This was very pathetic.
Ini sangat menyedihkan.
Eşhedü enla ilaha illallah.
Eşhedü enla ilaha illallah.
No!
Tidak ada!
And the covenant and the Messenger of Allah.
Dan perjanjian dan Rasulullah.
At sunrise, at sunset.
Saat matahari terbit, saat matahari terbenam.
Every moment you don't tell the place of the literary ...
Setiap saat Anda tidak memberi tahu tempat sastra ...
... I will cut the throat of one of the Alps.
... Aku akan memotong tenggorokan salah satu Alpen.
We are going!
Kita akan!
Iron bending.
Besi lentur.
Erkut!
Erkut!
That...
Air ...
...That.
... air.
Shut up!
Diam!
I said everything you wanted.
Saya mengatakan semua yang Anda inginkan.
A little water.
Sedikit air.
If Samsa happens to the brain ...
Jika Samsa terjadi pada otak ...
... I'll swim and salt your skin.
... Aku akan berenang dan menggarami kulitmu.
That...
Air ...
Does this rug fit on the looms of the chicks of apricot obese?
Apakah permadani ini cocok dengan alat tenun anak ayam aprikot yang gemuk?
Our main ...
Utama kami ...
... When are the daughters of Hayme chicks, Halime chicks
... Kapan anak perempuan dari anak ayam Hayme, anak perempuan Halime
... stop weaving rugs and became shoddy ties?
... berhenti menganyam karpet dan menjadi ikatan yang buruk?
We sat at the counter at sunrise.
Kami duduk di konter saat matahari terbit.
We woke up at sunset.
Kami bangun saat matahari terbenam.
At night, we used the pomegranate to our fingers.
Pada malam hari, kami menggunakan buah delima ke jari-jari kami.
Just to let it rest.
Biarkan saja.
Come on.
Ayo
Give up, Zöhre chick.
Menyerahlah, Zorkre cewek.
Do I say much?
Apakah saya banyak bicara?
Do you make these rugs fit on the rugs?
Apakah Anda membuat karpet ini pas di karpet?
You have a right.
Anda punya hak.
However, nothing is as before.
Namun, tidak ada yang seperti sebelumnya.
The place where we collect root dyes is willow.
Tempat kami mengumpulkan pewarna akar adalah willow.
If you boil it for days, it will not give full color, it will not hold the paint.
Jika Anda merebusnya selama berhari-hari, itu tidak akan memberikan warna penuh, itu tidak akan menahan cat.
Ecel came to the world, headache excuse.
Ecel datang ke dunia, alasan sakit kepala.
I know..
Aku tahu ..
.. the ambition of the snow is over.
.. ambisi salju sudah berakhir.
Babes!
Babes!
My Sisters!
My Sisters!
Is it very difficult to find the grasses that are less or less?
Apakah sangat sulit menemukan rumput yang kurang atau kurang?
Is it very difficult to weave the best of the rug?
Apakah sangat sulit untuk menenun karpet terbaik?
We continue together from the place left by Hayme mother.
Kami melanjutkan bersama dari tempat yang ditinggalkan ibu Hayme.
I know...
Saya tahu ...
... the daughters of Kayi Oba have separate skills in each finger.
... putri-putri Kayi Oba memiliki keterampilan terpisah di setiap jari.
Now let them see.
Sekarang biarkan mereka melihat.
What ingenuity will the chicks of the Kayı oba.
Kecerdasan apa yang akan dimiliki anak-anak burung Kaya oba.
I know.
Saya tahu
Such rugs will be woven on these looms.
Permadani seperti itu akan ditenun pada alat tenun ini.
Yeah.
Ya.
That's right.
Benar juga.
Even you will not look back at what you have touched before.
Bahkan Anda tidak akan melihat kembali apa yang telah Anda sentuh sebelumnya.
We met you again, Selcan hatun.
Kami bertemu Anda lagi, Selcan hatun.
Welcome.
Selamat datang
Mr. Dundar, you are right here.
Pak Dundar, Anda ada di sini.
Zöhre chick.
Zohre cewek.
We came here to crown peace.
Kami datang ke sini untuk memahkotai perdamaian.
We came as a friend.
Kami datang sebagai teman.
You wanted to see the rugs, princess.
Anda ingin melihat permadani, putri.
Here Basin.
Sini Basin.
Let's see...
Mari kita lihat ...
Osman Bey, they could not finish praise
Osman Bey, mereka tidak bisa menyelesaikan pujian
how durable was it?
seberapa tahan lama?
Say my hands ...
Katakan tanganku ...
... let's see this all together
... mari kita lihat ini bersama-sama
What does that heart look for in this baby son?
Apa yang hati itu cari pada bayi laki-laki ini?
These are ...
Ini adalah ...
... they know how to kidnap chickens from the market for money.
... mereka tahu cara menculik ayam dari pasar demi uang.
Then in ...
Kemudian pada ...
... they roam because I am brave.
... mereka berkeliaran karena saya berani.
Enough talk about it!
Cukup bicara tentang itu!
Tell me your money and we'll give you the amount.
Katakan uang Anda dan kami akan berikan jumlahnya.
Sold dog!
Anjing yang dijual!
Ah!
Ah!
Lord!
Tuhan!
Mr. Osman!
Osman!
Deyyuz!
Deyyuz!
Sold dog!
Anjing yang dijual!
It will be your turn.
Sekarang giliran Anda.
Do not hurry.
Luangkan waktu Anda.
Where's the literary?
Di mana sastra?
Where you will die!
Di mana Anda akan mati!
Give it!
Berikan itu!
Lord!
Tuhan!
Come on, God!
Ayo, Tuhan!
Mr. Osman!
Osman!
Lord!
Tuhan!
Where's the literary?
Di mana sastra?
He slipped into his sleepy sleep.
Dia tertidur lelap.
Father.
Ayah.
No, I hope.
Tidak, saya harap.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Osman.
Osman.
What happened to Osman, Dad?
Apa yang terjadi pada Osman, Ayah?
Tell the dervishes, girl.
Beritahu para darwis, gadis.
Let them walk through the forest thoroughly.
Biarkan mereka berjalan melalui hutan secara menyeluruh.
Horse of the canteen.
Kuda kantin.
What are you up to, Osman?
Apa yang Anda lakukan, Osman?
Who are you?
Siapa kamu
I have an important offer for you, Mr. Dundar.
Saya memiliki tawaran penting untuk Anda, Tn. Dundar.
Tell me.
Beritahu saya
Mr. Alişar is ambitious.
Pak Alişar ambisius.
But we can both do bigger things.
Tapi kita berdua bisa melakukan hal yang lebih besar.
You travel in dangerous waters, Kalanos.
Anda bepergian di perairan berbahaya, Kalanos.
Don't you know, Alişar without brain news ...
Apakah kamu tidak tahu, Alişar tanpa berita otak ...
... even the leaf does not move in the end soil.
... bahkan daunnya tidak bergerak di tanah ujung.
Alişar bey is nothing without us.
Alişar bey tidak ada artinya tanpa kita.
I know that well, Mr. Dundar.
Saya tahu itu, Tn. Dundar.
Beyond that, Kalanos.
Di luar itu, Kalanos.
The market is only in willow ...
Pasar hanya di willow ...
... not in Eskihisar.
... tidak di Eskihisar.
There are markets waiting to revive in our land.
Ada pasar yang menunggu untuk bangkit kembali di tanah kami.
These markets ...
Pasar ini ...
... poor and weak.
... miskin dan lemah.
But...
Tapi ...
... both of us
... kita berdua
... by reviving the markets in Byzantium and earning our profits
... dengan menghidupkan kembali pasar di Byzantium dan mendapatkan keuntungan kami
... we can add strength to our strength.
... kita dapat menambah kekuatan pada kekuatan kita.
What do you say?
Apa yang kamu katakan
Your Rug ...
Karpet Anda ...
... Your weaving
... tenun Anda
... among the bestsellers in Constantinople.
... di antara buku terlaris di Konstantinopel.
It means that people of Constantinople understand the good of the rug.
Ini berarti bahwa orang-orang Konstantinopel memahami kebaikan permadani.
What do you wish, princess?
Apa yang kamu inginkan, tuan putri?
Increasing your rugs ...
Meningkatkan permadani Anda ...
... producing more goods
... memproduksi lebih banyak barang
... we would like to sell it directly in Constantinople.
... kami ingin menjualnya langsung di Konstantinopel.
More rugs mean ...
Lebih banyak karpet berarti ...
... more girls
... lebih banyak gadis
... more countertops.
... lebih banyak countertops.
We are ready to give whatever it takes.
Kami siap memberikan apa pun yang diperlukan.
We do it together with Selcan hatun.
Kami melakukannya bersama Hatun Selcan.
Isn't that right, babe?
Benar kan, sayang?
If you are going to stay here, gold is important.
Jika Anda akan tinggal di sini, emas itu penting.
Hea ...
Hea ...
... if the gold was with maple ...
... Jika emas itu dengan maple ...
... they wouldn't get stuck in stone castles.
... mereka tidak akan terjebak dalam istana batu.
I will still think.
Saya masih akan berpikir.
Ya Allah.
Ya allah
My brother.
Adikku.
Live!
Hidup!
Osman kidnapped the gentleman.
Osman menculik pria itu.
Inform the thesis oba.
Menginformasikan oba tesis.
Go to the thesis and inform our master.
Pergi ke tesis dan informasikan kepada tuan kami.
I will carry the injured to the plains.
Saya akan membawa yang terluka ke dataran.
Okay brother.
Oke bro.
OK.
OK.
Deh!
Deh!
Gee.
Astaga
I saw that ...
Saya melihat itu ...
... your Aps give you so much value.
... Aps Anda memberi Anda banyak nilai.
Let's see...
Mari kita lihat ...
... which of them do you value more?
... siapa di antara mereka yang Anda nilai lebih?
Or is this a combative one?
Atau ini yang agresif?
Bloodless!
Sharpless!
You will account for what they have.
Anda akan menjelaskan apa yang mereka miliki.
Demon.
Iblis.
Esbab demon.
Esbab iblis.
You're gonna die.
Kau akan mati.
Or...
Atau ...
is this wild?
apakah ini liar?
He even has a war wound on his face.
Dia bahkan memiliki luka perang di wajahnya.
I am sorry that you will die impotently.
Saya menyesal bahwa Anda akan mati tanpa daya.
But...
Namun ...
Osman will tell when he will die.
Osman akan memberi tahu kapan dia akan mati.
Ha Osman?
Ha Osman?
Tell me ...
Katakan padaku ...
...which?
... yang mana?
I mean, the lovers ...
Maksudku, para kekasih ...
... Yusuf's dungeon was dark.
... Penjara Yusuf gelap.
That dark dungeon ...
Penjara gelap itu ...
... in the garden of light
... di taman cahaya
Was Yusuf's faith.
Adalah iman Yusuf.
What makes Joseph supreme ...
Apa yang membuat Joseph ...
what a well ...
apa yang baik ...
what Egypt,
apa Mesir,
nor dungeon.
atau penjara bawah tanah.
To get rid of the well to the light ...
Untuk menyingkirkan sumur ke cahaya ...
... edict to get out of the dungeon
... dekrit untuk keluar dari penjara bawah tanah
... to become a sultan in Egypt
... untuk menjadi sultan di Mesir
... ideas may be needed.
... ide mungkin diperlukan.
Not that...
Namun ...
... to be like Yusuf
... untuk menjadi seperti Yusuf
... faith is needed.
... iman dibutuhkan.
Amenna.
Amenna.
Faith...
Iman ...
... obvious to the victor
... jelas bagi pemenang
... the Iraqi one is near
... yang Irak sudah dekat
... makes the defeated victorious.
... membuat yang kalah menang.
May Allah make us free from the outside.
Semoga Allah membebaskan kita dari luar.
Amine.
Amin.
Yenipazar raid ...
Serangan Yenipazar ...
... in terms of the trust of the region
... dalam hal kepercayaan daerah
... has been bad.
... buruk.
Not that...
Namun ...
... when the market is re-established
... ketika pasar didirikan kembali
... informal from us
... informal dari kami
... as it will not open the counter.
... karena tidak akan membuka konter.
The Edebali ...
The Edebali ...
There is literary, Dundar bey.
Ada sastra, Dundar bey.
Did you say craft or trade?
Apakah Anda mengatakan kerajinan atau perdagangan?
... come to mind.
... datang ke pikiran.
Ahi means trouble.
Ahi berarti masalah.
For everyone...
Untuk semua orang ...
... means a big trouble.
... berarti masalah besar.
Neither me nor Alişar ...
Baik saya maupun Alişar ...
... we can't include him.
... kita tidak bisa memasukkannya.
The End of the ...
Akhir ...
... and even the absence of merchants ...
... dan bahkan tidak adanya pedagang ...
... to turn it into an opportunity.
... untuk mengubahnya menjadi peluang.
My nephew...
Keponakan saya ...
... keep your work tight.
... jaga agar pekerjaan Anda tetap ketat.
The pain of the people is still fresh, uncle.
Rasa sakit orang-orang masih segar, paman.
Even the blood in the marketplace did not dry out.
Bahkan darah di pasar tidak mengering.
Dominant ...
Dominan ...
... use it in our favor
... gunakan untuk kebaikan kita
... it won't work for us.
... itu tidak akan bekerja untuk kita.
This is not use, my nephew.
Ini tidak digunakan, keponakan saya.
Both ...
Kedua ...
... do you think I'm not upset?
... apakah kamu pikir aku tidak kesal?
So many people ...
Begitu banyak orang ...
... to eat grief and drink my tears?
... untuk makan kesedihan dan minum air mataku?
As soon as possible to revive the market ...
Sesegera mungkin untuk menghidupkan kembali pasar ...
... to serve the people of the people.
... untuk melayani rakyat.
Besides, everyone has seen that ...
Selain itu, semua orang telah melihat bahwa ...
... the market without the apricot Alps under my auspices ...
... Pasar tanpa aprikot Alps di bawah naungan saya ...
... is also suitable for hanging.
... juga cocok untuk menggantung.
This is ...
Ini ...
... will increase the inclination to us.
... akan meningkatkan kecenderungan untuk kita.
Is Dundar the same decision as you in Sofia?
Apakah Dundar keputusan yang sama dengan Anda di Sofia?
Sofia ...
Sofia ...
... made a promise to me with his commander Kalanos.
... membuat janji kepada saya dengan komandannya Kalanos.
The late wife, Yorgo Pulos ...
Almarhum istri, Yorgo Pulos ...
... will go its way.
... akan jalannya sendiri.
I wish the alliance with the enemy is as much as you think ...
Saya berharap aliansi dengan musuh sebanyak yang Anda pikirkan ...
... if you thought about Sheikh Edebiyi who came to our lands.
... jika Anda berpikir tentang Sheikh Edebiyi yang datang ke tanah kami.
Do not forget that Gundogdu and his son Mongol took it.
Jangan lupa bahwa Gundogdu dan putranya Mongol mengambilnya.
Literary has taken trouble wherever he went.
Sastra membawa masalah ke mana pun dia pergi.
Informally, we don't want bloodshed.
Secara informal, kami tidak ingin pertumpahan darah.
Don't worry, Zöhre chick.
Jangan khawatir, Zöhre cewek.
Evelallah. the blood to flow does not stop in the vein.
Evelallah. darah yang mengalir tidak berhenti di pembuluh darah.
I hope it is good?
Tidak, saya harap?
Is there a destruction, Mr. Dundar?
Apakah ada kehancuran, Tn. Dundar?
Abdurrahman.
Abdurrahman.
My father?
Ayah saya?
My brother?
adikku?
Come on Abdurrahman Gazi.
Ayo Abdurrahman Gazi.
Selamun aleykum.
Halo,
I Aleykümselam.
Aku Aleykümselam.
Where is my brother Abdurrahman Gazi?
Di mana saudaraku Abdurrahman Gazi?
Don't shut up, Abdurrahman Gazi.
Jangan diam, Abdurrahman Gazi.
What is my father's death?
Apa kematian ayahku?
Abdurrahman Gazi?
Abdurrahman Gazi?
Ertuğrul Beyim from Konya to Kayseri ...
Ertuğrul Beyim dari Konya ke Kayseri ...
... we went to the doctor with many men.
... kami pergi ke dokter dengan banyak pria.
Doctors in Kayseri, Gevher Sultan Hospital.
Dokter di Kayseri, Rumah Sakit Gevher Sultan.
... the disease is in your lungs.
... Penyakitnya ada di paru-paru Anda.
Treatment is required.
Diperlukan perawatan.
They said to stay here for a while.
Mereka berkata untuk tinggal di sini sebentar.
I hope its healing is Allah.
Saya berharap penyembuhannya adalah Allah.
God willing.
Mudah-mudahan.
Father..
Ayah ..
Sir, is there a destur?
Pak, apakah ada destur?
You're a pehlican dervish.
Anda seorang darwis pehlican.
Osman Bey and his Alps are lurking in the forest.
Osman Bey dan pegunungan Alpennya bersembunyi di hutan.
They were caught and taken away.
Mereka ditangkap dan dibawa pergi.
Who did this?
Siapa yang melakukan ini
We don't know, sir.
Kami tidak tahu, tuan.
Prepare my pusat.
Siapkan pusat saya.
Yarenler!
Yarenler!
The day is not a flirty but a day of flesh
Hari itu bukanlah genit tetapi hari daging.
We will not put Osman alone.
Kami tidak akan menempatkan Osman sendirian.
It is forbidden to us to stop informally, father.
Dilarang bagi kita untuk berhenti secara informal, ayah.
Ertuğrul beyim thinks of the oba even in that state.
Ertuğrul beyim memikirkan oba bahkan dalam keadaan itu.
He is afraid that the work of the stool will be delayed
Dia takut pekerjaan tinja akan tertunda
Ertuğrul, the son of Süleyman Shah, is the command of the brain;
Ertuğrul, putra Süleyman Shah, adalah komando otak;
My brother Dundar ...
Saudaraku Dundar ...
... he said to be my deputy.
... katanya menjadi deputi saya.
My sons ...
anak-anak saya ...
... their uncle,
... paman mereka,
... My guys,
... orang-orang saya,
... swear to your aghas.
... bersumpah demi agha Anda.
“Make things easy,” he said.
"Buat semuanya mudah," katanya.
Happy birthday, Dundar bey.
Selamat ulang tahun, Dundar bey.
The magnificence of the principality ...
Keagungan kerajaan ...
... the pot of might
... pot kekuatan
... your pusat be sharp, sir.
... pusatmu tajam, tuan.
I want my pus ...
Saya ingin nanah saya ...
... I knew it in your eyes.
... Aku tahu itu di matamu.
May you exist, babe.
Semoga Anda ada, sayang.
May you exist.
Semoga Anda ada.
Good luck my father
Semoga beruntung, ayahku
Thank you, girl.
Terima kasih sayang
May Allah make it clear, sir.
Semoga Allah menjelaskan, tuan.
The principality ...
Kerajaan ...
Happy birthday, my father.
Selamat ulang tahun, ayahku.
Thank you son.
Terima kasih, nak.
May Allah help you and your uncle.
Semoga Allah membantu Anda dan paman Anda.
It is my father's order.
Ini adalah perintah ayah saya.
It pays you allegiance ...
Itu membayar Anda kesetiaan ...
I wish to make your job easier.
Saya ingin membuat pekerjaan Anda lebih mudah.
My brother...
Saudaraku ...
... standing on his horse
... berdiri di atas kudanya
... will enter this plague.
... akan memasuki wabah ini.
You don't drop your face.
Anda tidak menjatuhkan wajah Anda.
Since...
Jika ...
... Ertuğrul is my order
... Ertuğrul adalah pesanan saya
... it is our duty to pay allegiance.
... itu adalah tugas kita untuk membayar kesetiaan kepada kita.
Mr. Dundar.
Pak Dundar.
Happy, Mr. Dundar.
Selamat, Tn. Dundar.
My brother...
Saudaraku ...
Is there any destim, sir?
Apakah ada tujuan, tuan?
Come Yaman.
Ayo Yaman.
Bey.
Bey.
They brought serious injuries to the Erkut alpi.
Mereka membawa luka serius ke Erkut alpi.
Iron bending was martyred.
Pembengkokan besi mati syahid.
How about you?
Bagaimana dengan anda
What do you say?
Apa yang kamu katakan
Where is my Osman?
Di mana Osman saya?
Where are the other alps?
Di mana Alpen lainnya?
They took them all away.
Mereka mengambil semuanya.
Kill me.
Bunuh aku
Kill.
Membunuh.
Down with the dog!
Turun dengan anjing!
Kill me!
Bunuh aku!
If...
Jika ...
... if you don't kill me now,
... jika kamu tidak membunuhku sekarang,
... your lungs
... paru-parumu
... I remove it with my teeth and feed it to the thighs.
... Saya menghapusnya dengan gigi saya dan memberi makan ke paha.
If you want so much ...
Jika Anda sangat ingin ...
Stop Salvador!
Hentikan Salvador!
Leave!
Jatuhkan!
Let's enjoy their death.
Mari kita nikmati kematian mereka.
Princess Sofia.
Putri Sofia.